Leena Lallmon

Summary

I'm a Software Engineer based in Montreal, Canada who enjoys problem solving. I am the co-creator of Fjord (fjord-framework.github.io ②), an open source framework that provides a real-time API Proxy for Apache Kafka. I have multiple years of experience in the Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems, and I am comfortable with Golang, AWS and Docker.

Professional Experience

Co-creator & Software Engineer, *Fjord*

2021 - present

- Utilizes languages and technologies such as JavaScript, AWS ECS, AWS Fargate, AWS Elasticache for Redis, Docker and Server-Sent Events
- Collaborated on the prototype of the API Server and Kafka Consumer process using Node.js, KafkaJS and MongoDB
- Isolated and containerized Fjord components using Docker for deployment to AWS cloud infrastructure
- Implemented distributed Kafka system to test Fjord
- Load tested to handle over 8500 concurrent connections
- Utilized a CLI tool that deploys all of Fjord's AWS components based on user's requirements
- Co-authored a comprehensive technical case study
 ☐ documenting design decisions

Full-Stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

2020 - 2021

Developed open-source software, some highlighted projects include:

- Ruby Blogger, a Ruby library command line developer tool to track exceptions
- Contact Manager, a JavaScript, Express, Bulma CRUD app with a Node API server
- **Spry**, a Kanban style Trello clone built with MongoDB, Express, React, Redux and axios

Skills

Backend Frontend Tooling Cloud Node.is JavaScript (ES6) Git AWS EC2 Github AWS ECS Express React Ruby Redux Docker AWS Fargate • AWS Elasticache for SQL HTML Linux • EventSource API Redis RESTful APIs AWS VPC Webhooks AWS ALB SSE GCP VM • Digital Ocean Droplet

Education

Software Engineering & Full Stack Development, Education Multi-year full-stack Software Engineering curriculum with mastery- based learning	2020 - 2021
Social Work, Cégep du Vieux Montréal	2008 - 2011